Guide to the Frank Altschul Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1884-1986
  - Subseries I.2: General Correspondence, 1906-1986
    - Gardner, Richard N, 1956-1977 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Gib, Gil (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Gifford, Ralph C, 1935-1945 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Gim-Goo, (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Goldsmith, Lucien, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Goodhart, Arthur--Oversize Clipping, 1968 (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 9)
    - Goodhart, Arthur, Cecily and Family, 1928-1951 (4 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 6 to 9)
    - Goodhart, Arthur, Cecily and Family, 1952-1962 (16 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1 to 16)
    - Goodhart, Arthur, Cecily and Family, 1962-1968 (8 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Goodhart, Arthur, Cecily and Family, 1967-1970 (7 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Goodhart, Arthur, Cecily and Family, 1970-1972 (4 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Goodhart, Charles and Miffy, 1960-1966 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Goodhart, Howard, 1927-1950 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Goodhart, Philip and Hattie Lehman, 1935-1948 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Goodhart, Philip, Valerie and Family, 1948-1966 (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Goodhart, Philip--Oversize Clipping, 1954 (Box 201 Oversize)
    - Goodhart, Sophie L., 1952-1955 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Gordan, Phyllis Goodhart and Family, 1953-1971 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Gor-Gri, (3 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Griffith, William E., 1960-1965 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Griswold, Erwin N, 1954-1965 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Gro-Gu (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Gross, Ernest A. and Kathryn, 1951-1975 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Ha-Han (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Haight, Anne Pardee Lyon (Mrs. Sherman P.), 1948-1977 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Halleck, Charles A., 1938-1973 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Hamilton, John D. M. and Rosamund (Rosie) Kittle, 1947-1974 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Hammerschlag, Emil and Rosita Gruenberg (Grenby), 1937-1948 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Hammerschlag, Dr. Ernst and Margo, 1961-1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Hammerschlag, Paul, Bertha and Rudolph Duschnitz, 1929-1940 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Hansen, Frederick D., 1952-1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Har-Haz (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Haskins, Mr. Caryl P., 1960-1970 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Hayman, Peter and Rosemary, 1962-1964 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - He-Hen (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Heilperin, Michael, 1947-1953 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Heineman, D., undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Heller, Ralph, Hannelotte and Bettina, 1933-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Heller, Richard, 1935-1964 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Hensel, H. Struve and Isabel, 1952-1967 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Her-Hez (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Herring, Pendleton, 1952-1957 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Herzog, Paul and Julie, 1962-1986 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Hess, Sara (Mrs. Alfred F.), 1953-1956 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Hi-Hop, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Hobson, Thayer, 1934-1966 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Holland, Harry A. and Marjorie, 1962-1967 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Hor-Hoz (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Horne, Anne and Peter, 1938-1959 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Houghton, Arthur A. Jr., 1951-1957 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Hoxsey, J.M.B, 1931-1945 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Hu-Huz (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Hughes, Thomas L, 1966-1974 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Hulbard, Deforest, 1944-1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Hunt, Lawrence, 1943-1968 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Huxley, Michael, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Hyde, Gordon E. and Louise, 1907-1969 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - I-In (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Institute for Mediterranean Affairs, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Invitations--Regents, 1979-1980 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Ir-Jam, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Jackson, Charles Douglas, 1948-1964 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Jackson, William Harding, 1935-1950 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Jan-Ji, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Jeidels, Otto, Tula and Family 1937-1954 (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Jo-Ju (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Johnson, Joseph E., 1952-1973 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Josten, Werner, Margaret and Family, 1934-1976 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Ka-Kel (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Kellems, Vivian, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Keller, Edwin P., 1947-1969 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Kellerman, Dons and Rudolph, 1965-1972 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Kelly, Dorothy, 1944-1947 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Kem-Ki (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Kennan, George Frost, 1947-1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Kiep, Otto C., Hanna Alves and Hildegard, 1932-1972 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Kindersely, Hugh, Nancy and Family, 1934-1976 (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Kindersely, Hugh and Rosie Hill, 1952-1976 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Kindersley, Robert and Gladys, 1938-1957 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Kl-Kn (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Knowles, John Ellis, 1944-1977 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Ko (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Kohnstamm, M., 1930 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Korn, Richard and Margaret Kaye (Peggy), 1953-1968 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Koshland, Daniel E. and Lucille, 1961-1974 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Kr-Ku (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Krim, Arthur B., 1965-1971 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - La-Laz (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Lacour-Gayet, Robert, 1925-1930 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Lang, Robert E. and Muriel (Mimi) Richardson, 1955-1971 (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Lash, Stephen Sycle and Wendy Lehman, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Lawrence, David, 1937-1959 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Lasker, Mary Woodard (Mrs. Albert D.), 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Lazard, Christian, 1923-1928 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Lazard Freres--Partners and Family, 1931-1940 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Larzard, Ginette (Mme. Andre), 1931-1971 (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 8 to 10)
    - Le-Lez (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Lehman, Allan S., 1941-1947 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Lehman, Arthur and Adele L., 1945-1949 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Lehman Brothers, 1951 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Lehman, Herbert H., 1923-1964 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Lehman, John R., 1957-1973 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Lehman, Orin, 1966-1970 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Lehman, Meyer, undated (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 12)
    - Lehman, Peter G., Peggy and Family, 1943-1944 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Lehman, Robert and Ruth B.O. (Kitty) Rohde, 1938-1955 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - S.D. Leidesdorf and Co., 1966-1968 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth S. and Annie Burr, 1938-1975 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Levis, William E., 1935-1947 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Li-Lip (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Lichetenstein, Walter, 1935-1964 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Linder, Harold and Bertha, 1948-1960 (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 15 to 16)
    - Linder, Harold and Bertha, 1961-1977 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Lo-Ly (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Loeb, John L., 1945-1952 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Lopata, Rosalynd, 1939-1941 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Lovestone, Jay, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Lowe, Charles Upton, Eileen Josten and Family, 1955-1979 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Lubin, Isador, 1950-1968 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Luce, Henry R. and Clare Booth, 1937-1972 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Lynch, Joseph B. and Kathleen, 1952-1976 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Mc (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - McAloney, S. Holt, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - McCloy, John J. and Ellen, 1952-1976 (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 2 to 3)
    - McCloy, John J.--Transportation Petition, undated (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 11)
    - McClure, Wallace, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - MacDermot, Brian, 1961-1969 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - MacDermot, Frank and Elaine, 1952-1975 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - McSweeney, Edward and Mary (Budge) Hartzell, 1941-1977 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Maa-Mal (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Mallory, Walter and Alice, 1948-1975 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Man-Mar (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Marris, A.D. (Denny), 1938-1945 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Martin, Harold, Rose and Madeline,Mas-Maz, Master, Arthur M., Hilda Altschul and Family, 1946-1976 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Mas-Maz (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Master, Arthur M., Hilda Altschul and Family, 1934-1969 (4 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Master, Hilda Altschul, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - May, George O., 1958 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Me-Mez (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Meeks, Samuel W., 1949-1970 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Merz, Charles and Evelyn, 1940-1959 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Meyer, Andre and Bella, 1938-1945 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1940-1959 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Mic-Miles (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Michaelis, Michael and Diana Tead, 1953-1961 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Mill-Miz (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Mladek, Jan V. and Meda Sokolova, 1949-1965 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Mod-Mon (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Moley, Raymond C., 1932-1967 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Monnet, Jean and Silvia, 1954-1967 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Monroe, Daniel L., 1945-1973 (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Moo-Morg (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1954-1968 (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Mori-Moz (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Morse, David, 1962-1970 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Mosely, Philip E., 1947-1972 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Moyers, Bill, 1967-1968 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Mu-My (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Muir, Malcolm, 1955-1979 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Muller, Andre and Helen Maguire, 1966-1974 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Na-Nez, (3 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 8 to 10)
    - Neuberger, Richard L., and Maurine, 1954-1960 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Ni-Nu (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - O-Ol (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Oakes, John B., 1955-1973 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Ogburn, Charlton, 1946-1962 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Om-Oz (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1954-1963 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Ormerod, Cyril Berkely (Bill), 1953-1969 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Overseas News Agency, 1945-1950 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Owen, Henry D, 1968-1971 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Pa-Paz (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Paneth, Friedrich Alolph (Fritz), 1949-1965 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Paneth, Otto C. and Marie, 1955-1975 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Patterson, Robert P. and Margaret W., 1952-1961 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Pea-Po, (3 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Powell, Eleanor A. (Mrs. Robert) and Family, 1964-1975 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Pr-Pu (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Q (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Raa-Raz (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Random, L. R., Edith Rosenheim and Family, 1938-1941 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Rea-Rez (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Redmond, Roland L and Sara Delano, 1936-1949 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Redmond, Roland L. and Lydia di San Faustino, 1954-1963 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Reid, Ogden Rogers, Helen and Family, 1954-1966 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Refugees A-D, 1938-1942 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Refugees F-Z, 1938-1942, (4 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Reinhardt, Mary Woodard, 1935-1940 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Reinhardt, Paul, 1939-1944 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Rh-Ri (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Rheintein, Sidney, 1950-1967 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Richard, Rose Marie, 1955-1980 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Ritcher, Jeanne, 1940-1970 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Roa-Rob (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Robert College of Istanbul, Turkey, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Roberts, George, 1952-1968 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Roc-Roo (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Roesler, Carol, 1954-1970 (2 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Rollins, Carl P. and Margaret, 1959-1969 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Ros-Roz (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Rosenthal, Grace and Family, 1947-1954 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Rosenwald, William, 1956-1976 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Rossbach, J. Howard, 1941-1975 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Rostow, Eugene, 1959-1972 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Ru-Ry (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Saa-Saz (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Sachs, Alexander, 1940-1966 (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Sachs, Howard and Eleanor (Elie), 1951-1975 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Sargeant, Howland H., 1956-1970 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Saturday Review, 1955-1969 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Sca-Sco (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Scandrett, Richard B., 1941-1954 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Scheuer, Sidney H., 1963-1978 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Scott, John, 1957-1976 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Se-Sh (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Shipley, Arthur Everett, 1906-1907 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Shulman, Marshall D., 1955-1972 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Shuster, George N., 1953-1976 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Si-Sm (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Silvercruys, Robert and Rosemary, 1954-1965 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Sn-Sp (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Spofford, Charles M., 1950-1970 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Sta-Sto (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Stamford, 1938-1951 (3 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Stamford, A-K, 1955-1956 (3 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 7 to 9)
    - Stamford, L-Z, 1956-1961 (4 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Stamford--General, 1961-1972 (6 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 5 to 10)
    - Stamford--General, 1973-1979 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Steel, Johannes, 1934-1947 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Stone, Michael, 1963-1964 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Stra (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Straus, Roger William, 1947-1968 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Stre-Stro (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Streit, Clarence, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Stu-Sz (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Sullivan, E. Constance, 1955-1974 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Syminton, Charles J., 1952-1975 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Ta-Tay (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Taylor, H. Kenneth, 1955-1961 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Tea-Thu, (2 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Thompson, Kenneth, 1958-1978 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Ti-To (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Tompkins, Boylston Adams and Eleanore Marshall (Tommy and Ellie), 1948-1971 (4 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 6 to 9)
    - Tompkins, Eleanore Marshall (Mrs. B.A.), 1972-1976 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Tr-Ty (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Triffin, Robert, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Trowbridge, Alexander, 1954-1972 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Tyser, Granville, 1935-1970 (2 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 4 to 5)
    - U (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Ungar, Felix L., Margarethe (Gretl) and Family, 1938-1951 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Va-Ve (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Valentine, Alan, 1936-1964 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Vanderbilt, William H. and Anne Colby, 1957-1961 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Van Cise, Clinton S. and Mellicent, 1959-1969 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Vi-Waz, (2 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Walsh, Germaine Bouffet (Mrs. Frank), 1961-1975 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Warburg, James, 1955-1969 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Ward, Barbara (Lady Robert Jackson), 1948-1977 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Washburn, Abbott McConnell and Mary Brennan, 1949-1972 (5 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 8 to 12)
    - Wasson, R. Gordon and Valentina Guerken, 1948-1970 (2 Folders) (Box 58, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Wea-Wez (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Webster, Bethuel M. and Family, 1960-1976 (4 Folders) (Box 58, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Weill, Lucie, 1952-1971 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Weiller, Paul Louis, 1937-1941 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Wha-Who (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - White, Dudley A. and Alice, 1946-1957 (2 Folders) (Box 58, Folder 11 to 12)
    - White, Dudley A. and Alice, 1946-1957 (4 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 1 to 4)
    - White, Alice (Mrs. Dudley A.) and Family, 1958-1972 (3 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Whitman, Ann, 1953-1975 (2 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Wia-Wiz (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Winton, David and Family, 1952-1967 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Wise, Hilda Jane Lehman and Family, 1967-1974 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Wm-Wy (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Wohlstetter, Albert and Roberta, 1959-1967 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Wolfers, Arnold and Doris, 1946-1973 (3 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 15 to 17)
    - Wolfers, Arnold and Doris, 1946-1973 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Wriston, Henry M. and Marguerite (Peggy), 1955-1979 (7 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 2 to 8)
    - X Y Z (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Yost, Charles W., 1966-1972 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Youngman, Althya, 1946-1977 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Yunko, Eva Sheldon, 1951-1978 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified Correspondence, 1939-1949 (Box 60, Folder 13)
- Series II: Charles and Camilla Altschul, 1863-1932
  This series contains the papers of Frank Altschul's parents, Charles and Camilla Altschul. Though his family was American, Charles was born in England and studied Germany, and he retained a strong interest in European politics and history throughout his life. His papers contain research notes, annotated subject files and correspondence on many topics, including European economics, social issues such as health care and birth control, and research on foreign language publications in the United States. Several files hold correspondence and articles written in response to his writings, including his monograph "The American Revolution in Our School Textbooks" and articles on war debt and war guilt after World War I. The series also holds correspondence between Charles Altschul and his cousin, Dr. Paul Hammerschlag of Vienna. The series contains smaller amounts of information on other members of the Altschul family, such a family tree, a marriage scrapbook for Frank Altschul's uncle and aunt, William and Rosita Altschul, Rosita's diary, and an art history notebook kept by Maria Altschul. Information on Camilla is limited to condolences upon her death in 1952.
  - General Correspondence A-Z, 1915-1927 (5 Folders) (Box 61, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Correspondence with Paul Hammerschlag, 1909-1927 (8 Folders) (Box 61, Folder 6 to 13)
  - Correspondence with Paul Hammerschlag, 1921-1930 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Articles on the Writings of Charles Altschul
    - "The American Revolution In Our School Textbooks," 1917-1923 (3 Folders) (Box 62, Folder 2 to 4)
    - "German Militarism and its German Critics," 1918 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - "Europe's Debt and Our Own," 1921 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - "Need of Precise Definition of What Constitutes 'War Guilt'," 1926 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Occasional Papers, 1927-1932 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Condolences--Charles Altschul, 1927 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Condolences--Camilla Altschul, 1927 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Correspondence, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Family
    - Album of Telegrams, Toasts, and Poems on the Occasion of the Marriage of William and Rositta Altschul, 1887 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Maria Altschul--Notebook on Art History, undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Rositta Altschul--Diary, 1887-1891 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - "Die Familie Josephson"--Family Tree, undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Charles Altschul--Published Writings, 1917-1927 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - "Comments on Some Controversies Regarding Responsibility for the World War," by Charles Altschul--Unpublished Paper, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Subject Files
    - Foreign Language Press, 1923-1924 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Germany and the Germans, 1863-1921 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Late German Newspapers--Notes and Clippings, 1922-1923 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Europe, Economics and Other Topics (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - European Politics--Clippings, 1915-1916 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - World War I--Notes, Articles, and Newspaper Clippings (2 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 5 to 6)
- Series III: Writings by Frank Altschul and Others, 1910-1974
  This series contains material relating to Frank Altschul's many speeches, letters to editors, editorials, book reviews, essays, and articles. Most files contain a draft or copy of the finished piece, as well as notes and related correspondence and articles. There are also several files concerning the publication of "A Catalogue of the Altschul Collection of George Meredith in the Yale University Library" and biographical articles about Altschul. Files have been divided by document type and further arranged alphabetically by title. The series also holds a small number of speech drafts by Altschul's acquaintances, including Raymond Buell, Arther L. Goodhart, and playwright Clare Boothe Luce, which can be found under the heading "Writings by Others."
  - Catalogue of the Altschul Collection of George Meredith in the Yale University Library 1931
    - Correspondence and Related Items, 1923-1971, (3 Folders) (Box 65, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Printing of the Catalogue--Correspondence, 1930-1932 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Acknowledgements for Receipt of Catalogue, 1931 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Speeches and Related Correspondence
    - Untitled Speeches, undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - "Reparations and War Debts"--Address at the Academy of Political Science, 1932 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Untitled, 23 November 1937 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Kiwanis Club, 1941 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - "The Role of the Republican Party in the Present Emergency," 1942 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Meeting of the Fifth Ward Club, 1942 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Notes and Drafts, 1951-1953 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - "A New Approach to the Soviet Union," 1952 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - School of Advanced International Studies: Introduction of George Kennan, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Woodrow Wilson Award Dinner, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - "Some Aspects of Soviet American Relations"--Riverside Church, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Woodrow Wilson Commemorative Committee, 1954 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Stamford Forum, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Lehman Speech, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Roxbury Community Association, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - United Jewish Appeal, 1957 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Stamford High School, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Stamford Forum on World Affairs, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Broadcast on Rockefeller Fund, Panel II Report, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Aspen Executive Seminar, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Exchange Club of Stamford, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Temple Beth-El, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - National Businessmen's Council, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - "The Democratic Process and the Berlin Crisis"--Yale University, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - WBAI-FM Broadcast, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Princeton Club, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Air Force Reserve Officers, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - WBAI Broadcast, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Lotos Club Luncheon, 1961 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - WBAI Broadcast, 1961 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - National Planning Association, 1961 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - "Cuba: A Turning Point in World History"-- Army Reserve Training Center, 1962 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - AFL-C10 Free Trade Union News, 1964 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified Draft, undated (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Letters To Editors and Related Correspondence, 1910-1974
    - New York Sun, 1910 November 10 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - New York Times, 1939 August 17 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1941 December 4 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - New York Times, 1942 December 20 (2 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 11 to 12)
    - New York Times, 1944 July 16 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - New York Herald Tribune and New York Times, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - New York Times, 1948 July 25 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - New York Times, 1949 April 10 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - New York Times, 1952 October 29 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - New York Times, 1953 June 21 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - New York Times, 1955 November 23 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - New York Times, 1957 February 11 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - New York Times, 1957 September 8 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - New York Times, 1958 January 13 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - New Statesman, 1958 February 22 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - New York Times, 1958 September 14 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - New York Times, 1960 May 26 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - New York Times, 1960 October 7 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - New York Times, 1960 December 1 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1961 May 3 (Box 69, Folder 13)